<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Theoretical Computer Science -- Swansea University</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Theoretical Computer Science -- Swansea University</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CCC 2025 in Swansea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-09-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-09-08/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;CCC 2025 was an exceptional gathering that perfectly balanced intellectual stimulation with natural beauty. The conference delivered a series of captivating talks that challenged and inspired attendees, while the excursion to Gower provided a refreshing counterpoint to the intense academic discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCC 2025 Comes to Swansea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-20/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This September Swansea will be hosting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://swansea-theory.github.io/conferences/CCC2025&#34;&gt;CCC 2025 Continuity, Computability, Constructivity - From Logic to Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;CCC 2025 Website Screenshot&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Screenshot%202025-06-20%20at%2015.10.04.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giovanni Solda on Statistical Learning of Graphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-16/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This Thursday Giovanni Solda will give a talk on statistical learning of graphs as a part of our theory seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; In the first part of this talk, I aim to give an introduction to two frameworks that describe when a family of functions can be considered to be learnable, namely PAC and online learnability, and discuss the relationship between them. In the second part, we will apply these frameworks to study the graphs such that the family of their isomorphic copies (with some constraints to be made precise) are learnable.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mukesh on Formally Verified Verifiable Group Generators </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Mukesh will give a talk on Formally Verified Verifiable Group Generators as a part of our seminar series this Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic voting (e-voting) requires a trusted setup to initiate an election process. This setup must be transparent to maintain the integrity of the election. A crucial aspect of this trusted setup involves generating group generators for a finite cyclic group, which are then used in cryptographic algorithms deployed within the voting system. Although computing group generators is generally not considered a difficult problem, election verifiability – where every step can be ascertained by independent third parties – excludes many of them, as they fail to provide verifiable evidence of correctness. In this work, we present a formally verified implementation of the group generator algorithm A.2.3 and the group generator verification algorithm A.2.4, specified in the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), FIPS 186-4, in the Coq theorem prover. These two algorithms are highly sought-after methods to compute and verify group generator(s), respectively, because their outcomes can be established independently by third parties. Our formalisation captures all the requirements specified in algorithms A.2.3 and A.2.4 using the expressive type system of the Rocq theorem prover. We evaluate the group generator algorithm within the Rocq theorem prover itself to produce group generators, thereby only trusting the Rocq and its evaluation mechanism. In fact, our implementation is so efficient that it can compute the group generators used in real-world democratic elections in 30 min on a M3 laptop. The source code of this formalisation is available at GitHub [1].&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof and Computation Autumn School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-03/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Proof&amp;amp;Coomputation.png&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📢 The international autumn school &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Proof and Computation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; will take place from &lt;strong&gt;14–20 September 2025&lt;/strong&gt; in Herrsching near Munich. As a part of it, Ulrich Berger will deliver a course on Program extraction in higher-order logic.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manlio Valenti on the computational strength of a Hausdorff oracle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-06-02/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This Thursday Manlio will give a talk &amp;ldquo;On the computational strength of a Hausdorff oracle&amp;rdquo; as a part of our seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Hausdorff dimension is one of the most important notions of dimension in geometric measure theory. It provides a means to describe the &amp;ldquo;size&amp;rdquo; of a set in terms of &amp;ldquo;how tightly&amp;rdquo; it can be covered with open sets. Recent work has highlighted an interesting connection between the Hausdorff dimension of a set and the computability-theoretical properties of its points. In particular, the effective (Hausdorff) dimension of a point can be defined in terms of its (in)compressibility, so that incompressible (aka random) points have maximum effective dimension. The Point-to-Set Principle states that the Hausdorff dimension of a set can be obtained as the supremum of the effective dimension of its points relative to a fixed parameter (also called oracle). This raises a natural question: how hard is it to compute such an oracle and what is its computational strength? In this talk, we will discuss some recent results in this direction. This is joint work with Ben Koch, Elvira Mayordomo, Arno Pauly, and Cecilia Pradic.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davide Trotta&#39;s talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-05-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-05-06/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This Thursday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://trottadavide.github.io/&#34;&gt;Davide Trotta&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Padova will give a talk on &amp;ldquo;A topos for extended Weihrauch degrees&amp;rdquo; as a part of our seminar series.**Abstract:**Weihrauch reducibility [2] is a key notion of reducibility between computational problems that is useful to calibrate the uniform computational strength of a multi-valued function. Such reducibility provides a framework where one can formalize questions such as “which theorems can be transformed continuously or computably into another?”&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weihrauch problems as containers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-04-30/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ian Price will give a talk on &amp;ldquo;Weihrauch problems as containers&amp;rdquo; as a part of our seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weihrauch problems can be regarded as containers over the category of projective represented spaces and Weihrauch reductions correspond exactly to container morphisms. Using this characterisation, a number of operators over Weihrauch degrees, including the pomposition of degrees, arise naturally from the theory of polynomial functors.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are at the 41st British Colloquium for Theoretical Computer Science at Strathclyde University (Glasgow)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-04-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-04-14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgq9iGCNeaa6RTCBmJOoVqP5ottW0DwOA8fg5qeiTjvhYaREW-HKLxXkKVVTfOpQLxL-BNrKbUSKLytS18idfkh2uAphruHOr2cK6kEcfvu7CQctoNv5xMnqStODKELz9T69y7-wiC6sVBvVGIF-HRm3Gel_4ENo3aNG3Qro5nu6xrylRxWXJd3eYOgMczz/s2048/PhotoBCTCS2025.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;BCTCS 2025 at Strathclyde University, Glasgow&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marek Jezinski, Alec Critten, Harry Bryant and Olga Petrovska are currently attending the 41st British Colloquium for Theoretical Computer Science at Strathclyde University, Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Threshold Problems for Orbits of Semigroup Actions by Eike</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-04-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-04-02/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today Eike Neumann will give a talk on Threshold Problems for Orbits of Semigroup Actions as a part of our theory seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the following computational problem: Given a real function g on a space X, a compactly generated semi-group S acting on X, and a point x in X, is g positive on every point of the orbit of x under S?&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giorgio Genovesi on Characterizing Regular Countable Second Countable Spaces in Second Order Arithmetic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-03-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-03-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s seminar talk is by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giorgio Genovesi from Leeds, who will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;be talking about countable second countable topological spaces in the context of reverse mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Characterizing Regular Countable Second Countable Spaces in Second Order Arithmetic&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hideki Tsuiki visiting Swansea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-01-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-01-23/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;Hideki Tsuiki in Swansea&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/pro-sgPnZdmh.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Hideki Tsuiki from Kyoto University is visiting Swansea University from 22nd to 24th of January. Yesterday, he gave a talk on &lt;em&gt;Coinductive View of Shadows of 3D Fractals&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oliver Kullmann&#39;s talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-01-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-01-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today Oliver Kullmann will give a talk on Automated search for special Latin squares as a part of our Seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Latin squares have been studied since the days of Euler. After some overview on the history and background, an effort for a complete enumeration of special types of Latin squares of order 13, by as completely automated means as possible (which is currently actually not possible), will be presented and evaluated. The main method here is Cube-and-Conquer, a kind of 2-stage SAT-solving (as invented by the presenter). Quite some fine-tuning of representation and choice of solver was needed, and will be discussed (at some high level)&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matteo Acclavio visiting Swansea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-11-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-11-28/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Next week&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar will be given by &lt;a href=&#34;https://profiles.sussex.ac.uk/p623544-matteo-acclavio&#34;&gt;Matteo Acclavio&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Sussex, who is visiting us for a few days. The topic will be a new logical framework for concurrent programs, abstract below.&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; A new logical framework for concurrent programs&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Designing logical frameworks to reason about the properties of concurrent programs while accurately capturing the essence of concurrency is a challenging task.&lt;br&gt;
The main difficulties can be traced back to the syntactic constraints of the languages used for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galileo Sartor&#39;s talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-11-13/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;theory seminar talk will be by Galileo Sartor on &amp;ldquo;Representing and reasoning with legal aspects of traffic rules for autonomous vehicles&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will give an overview of a modular system for representing and reasoning with legal aspects of traffic rules for autonomous vehicles.&lt;br&gt;
We focus on a subset of the United Kingdom&amp;rsquo;s Highway Code (HC) related to junctions.&lt;br&gt;
As human drivers and automated vehicles (AVs) will interact on the roads, especially in urban environments, we claim that an accessible, unitary, high-level computational model should exist and be applicable to both users.&lt;br&gt;
Autonomous vehicles introduce a shift in liability that should not bring disadvantages or increased burden on human drivers.&lt;br&gt;
The proposed system is built of three main components: a natural language interface, using Logical English, used to encode the rules; an internal representation of the rules in Prolog; and a simple multi-agent-based simulation environment, built in NetLogo. The three components interact: Logical English is internally translated in Prolog, and the resulting code (along with some support code) interfaces with NetLogo with a bridge.&lt;br&gt;
Such a modular approach enables the different components to carry different ``burdens&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; in the overall system; it also allows replacing modules.&lt;br&gt;
With the NetLogo simulation, we can visualize the effect of the modeled rules as well as validate the system with a simple dynamic running scenario.&lt;br&gt;
Designated agents monitor the behaviour of the vehicles for compliance and record potential violations where they occur. The information on potential violations is then utilized by validator agents, to determine whether the violation is punishable, differentiating between exceptions and cases.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Georg Moser visiting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-30/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Georg Moser, Prof of Computer Science at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uibk.ac.at/en/&#34;&gt;University of Innsbruck&lt;/a&gt;, is visiting again this week to continue our work on the Royal Society funded project&lt;em&gt;MARRY: MARRYing the analyses of feasible algorithms and problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to effective fractal dimension by Benjamin Koch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-25/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s theory seminar will be given by Benjamin Koch, who will give as an introduction to effective fractal dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this talk is to give an overview of effective fractal dimension, which is an application of computability theory to geometric measure theory. I will start with an overview of two of the most important notions of dimension in classical measure theory, the Hausdorff and packing dimensions. Following this will be the formulation of so-called effective dimensions for points in R^n via Kolmogorov complexity. The highlight of the study of effective dimension thus far has been the “point-to-set principle”, which connects the effective dimension of points in R^n to the classical dimension of the subsets in which they reside. I will discuss a handful of the results that have come from this connection, which include an alternate proof of the Kakeya conjecture in R^2, an improved lower bound on the Hausdorff dimension of Furstenburg sets (which generalize Kakeya sets in R^2), and a generalization of an upper bound on the Hausdorff dimension of intersections and products of subsets of R^n&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory Seminar Series</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-21/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The theory seminar tomorrow will be given by Eike on &amp;ldquo;Robust Decidability of Escape Problems for General Non-Linear Systems.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A wide range of problems from a diverse range of areas can be formulated as &amp;ldquo;escape problems&amp;rdquo;: does a given point escape a set under the iteration of a function, or do all points in a given set escape the set under the function.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk on Assuring non-functional requirements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-04/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This summer &amp;amp; autumn, our department is hosting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof &lt;a href=&#34;https://www4.uib.no/en/find-employees/Magne.Haveraaen&#34;&gt;Magne Haveraaen&lt;/a&gt; (University Bergen, Norway)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of his involvement in ∆QSD group, he is organising a seminar talk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Assuring non-functional requirements”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research visit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t-powell.github.io/&#34;&gt;Thomas Powell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://researchportal.bath.ac.uk/en/persons/davide-barbarossa&#34;&gt;Davide Barbarossa&lt;/a&gt; (Bath University) are visiting Swansea this week. This afternoon Thomas will give a talk on the &amp;ldquo;Rates of convergence for stochastic processes&amp;rdquo; as a part of our seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eike was invited to give a talk in Kochel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-09/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;We are glad to inform that Eike Neumann was invited to talk at the Seminar on Computable Topology, which will take place in Kochel, Germany on 13-15 September.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoSCAI 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-12/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Arnold, Monika, Bertie and Jay went to Grenoble 1-4 July to attend the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://miai.univ-grenoble-alpes.fr/events/workshop-grenoble-swansea-on-ai-1453893.kjsp&#34;&gt;GoSCAI workshop&lt;/a&gt; and discussion of research opportunities with Grenoble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Grenoble_Campus_2016.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excursion to Gower</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Our Agda Implementors Meeting finished today with a lovely walk in Gower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;Gower Walk&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/olga-gower7.jpeg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agda Implementors Meeting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.portal.chalmers.se/agda/Main/AIMXXXVIII&#34;&gt;38th Agda Implementors&amp;rsquo; Meeting&lt;/a&gt; is taking place at the Computational Foundry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from Monday 13 to Saturday 18 May 2024. It will be hosted by the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Theoretical Computer Science Research Group,&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fahad Alhabardi passed his PhD viva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-05-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Fahad Alhabardi for passing his PhD (supervised by Anton Setzer and Arnold Beckmann) viva today! Thanks to the external examiner Conor McBride from Strathclyde University, the internal examiner Ulrich Berger, and the chair Bertie Mueller.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Máté Szabó&#39;s talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-04-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-04-18/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hsmt.ox.ac.uk/people/dr-mate-szabo&#34;&gt;Máté Szabó&lt;/a&gt; is visiting Swansea. He will give a talk today as a part of our theory seminar series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gödel&amp;rsquo;s and Post&amp;rsquo;s Proofs of the Incompleteness Theorem&lt;/strong&gt;This talk examines and compares two strikingly different proofs of the first incompleteness theorem. The first proof of the theorem was famously published by Kurt Gödel in 1931. However, during the previous decade, Emil Post already made significant breakthroughs in this topic, even though he was unable to publish his work for various reasons. After taking a short look at Gödel&amp;rsquo;s diagonal proof, we will engage in more detail with Post&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known proof. The latter proof is purely syntactic, and computer scientists of the day could recognize Post&amp;rsquo;s approach as presenting one of the earliest term rewrite systems. By the end of the talk the audience will hopefully agree with Post stating that “with the Principia Mathematica as a common starting point [i.e. of Gödel and Post], the roads followed towards our common conclusions are so different that much may be gained from a comparison of these parallel evolutions”.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swansea Theory Group attends the 40th British Colloquium for Theoretical Computer Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-28/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Monika, Faron, Olga, Filippos, Iain and James are attending the 40th British Colloquium for Theoretical Computer Science (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bctcs2024.github.io/&#34;&gt;BCTCS 2024&lt;/a&gt;) hosted by the University of Bath. This year is it also collocated with the 5th Southern and Midlands Logic Seminar.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCA 2024: Call for Submissions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-15/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Twenty-First International Conference on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computability and Complexity in Analysis (CCA 2024) will take place on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 15-18, 2024 here in Swansea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computable analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complexity on real numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computable numbers, subsets and functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theory of representations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computable differential equations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Randomness and computable measure theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithmic fractal dimension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective descriptive set theory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weihrauch complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverse analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constructive analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain theory and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realizability theory and analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Models of computability on real numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real number algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exact real number arithmetic
Submission deadline: April 29, 2024. For more information, click below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_external image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://cca-net.de/cca2024/&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mukesh Tiwari joined Swansea University</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-03-14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;We are happy that Mukesh Tiwari joined Swansea University recently. Today he will give a talk as a part of out theory seminar series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formalizing linear algebra over semirings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Linear algebra over real numbers (field algebraic structure) is a powerful mathematical tool for understanding and solving a wide range of computing problems. Nonetheless, it is not without its limitations, as a specific implementation tailored to one problem may not be readily applicable to solve another, i.e., it does not generalise well. In this talk, I will present a certified implementation of several linear algebraic methods such as matrix addition, matrix multiplication, matrix exponentiation, and&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRes Viva </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-29/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Olivia Weston for passing the MRes Viva! The examiners were Simon Fowler and Ulrich Berger. First supervisor was Cecilia Pradic.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tonicha Crook passed her PhD viva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-22/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Tonicha Crook passed her PhD viva today. The examiners were Pieter Collins (Maastricht) and Faron Moller (Swansea). The title of her PhD thesis is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;omputable Analysis and Game Theory: From Foundations to Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The PhD was supervised by Arno Pauly.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pieter Collins visiting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-19/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com/u/1/blog/post/edit/304872973678281747/9042283851169225809#&#34;&gt;Pieter Collins&lt;/a&gt; is currently visiting us from Maastricht. Today he will give a talk on &amp;ldquo;Verified Verification: Formal Proofs of Rigorous Numerical Methods for Model-Checking Dynamic Systems&amp;rdquo; as a part of our Theory Seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-02-02/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iss-www.swansea.ac.uk/staff/manlio.valenti/&#34;&gt;Manlio Valenti&lt;/a&gt;, together with his collaborators &lt;a href=&#34;https://meetings.ams.org/math/jmm2024/meetingapp.cgi/Person/26501&#34;&gt;David Reed Solomon&lt;/a&gt; and Damir Dzhafarov,  submitted the paper “The tree pigeonhole principle in the Weihrauch degrees”:&lt;a href=&#34;%20https://meetings.ams.org/math/jmm2024/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/29664%20&#34;&gt; https://meetings.ams.org/math/jmm2024/meetingapp.cgi/Paper/29664&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Trotta visiting Swansea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-12-01/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to extend a warm welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://trottadavide.github.io/&#34;&gt;Davide Trotta&lt;/a&gt;, a
postdoctoral researcher at the Department of Computer Science at the University
of Pisa in Italy. Davide brings his knowledge and expertise to our community,
and we are excited to have him as a guest speaker in our upcoming seminar
series, which will take place on Monday, 4 December in our Theory Lab.&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Categorifying computable reducibilities&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; One of the most relevant notions of categorical logic which
enabled the study of logic from a purely algebraic perspective is the notion of
a (hyper)doctrine, introduced in a series of seminal papers by F.W. Lawvere to
synthesize the structural properties of logical systems. In this talk, I will
introduce this categorical approach to logic and explain how various notions
well-known in computability can be framed within this categorical framework.In particular, I will present categorical formulations in
terms of Lawvere doctrines for the Medvedev, Muchnik, and Weihrauch
reducibilities.Finally, I will discuss some universal properties of such
doctrines, showing how this study enables us to identify, from an abstract
perspective, the common features of these notions of reducibility.This talk is based on joint work with Manlio Valenti and
Valeria de Paiva.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CCA 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-27/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Computability and Complexity Analysis conference is coming to Swansea next year. It will take place in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swansea.ac.uk/computational-foundry/&#34;&gt;Computational Foundry&lt;/a&gt; on 11-14 July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch this space for more updates.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-14/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;picture&gt;

    
      
        
        
        
        
        
        
    &lt;img
      loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
      decoding=&#34;async&#34;
      alt=&#34;&#34;
      
        class=&#34;image_figure image_internal image_unprocessed&#34;
        src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Teal%20Alcohol%20Ink%20Trust%20Yourself%20Quote%20Facebook%20Post.jpg&#34;
      
      
    /&gt;

    &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giovanni Solda visiting Swansea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-10/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Next week &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.ugent.be/web/person/giovanni-solda-0/publications/en&#34;&gt;Giovanni Solda&lt;/a&gt; is visiting us from Ghent. He will give a talk on &amp;ldquo;A combinatorial principle weak over weak systems yet strong over strong systems&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Abstract:***Better quasi orders (henceforth bqos) are a strengthening of the notion of well quasi order. Even if their definition is more complicated, the former enjoy nice closure properties that make them, in a way, easier to work with than the latter: this feature made bqos an&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory Blog is Back!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-11-08/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://swansea-theory.blogspot.com/p/about-us.html%20&#34;&gt;Swansea University Theory Group&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s new blog. Follow us for updates!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Swansea Theory Group is internationally renowned for its research
in Logic in Computer Science. The active research areas are:
Computability Theory, Computational Complexity, Proof Theory, Type
Theory, Game Theory, Algorithms,&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
